

Springfield. Massachusetts

[(413) 472-9082 | ■ julioapaton@gmail.com

Summary.

C++ Senior Software Engineer with 8+ years experience, has led teams to deliver critical applications in international defense programs. Motivated to continue to learn and grow as a professional and to help other team members to achieve their full potential. A Spaniard recently moved to the United States who is looking forward to making his next contribution.

Work Experience_

Tecnobit S.L.U. (Tactical Communications)

Valdepeñas, Spain

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Apr. 2021 - Present

- Mentoring new members of the team.
- · Remote communication with the client for requirement specification and support.
- Design, develop and testing of Tactical Data Link solution software.
- In-depth use of modern C++, STL, Boost, TCP/IP communications and multi-threading.

Tecnobit S.L.U. (Optronic Systems)

Valdepeñas, Spain

Jan. 2020 - Mar. 21

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Use of bug finding tools such as AddressSanitizer and Valgrind.
- Embedded software design and development in C/C++.
- Remote and on-site support to client.
- · CI of SW components.
- Technologies used include C++14, Xilinx SDK, Yocto Project and Jenkins.

Tecnobit S.L.U. (Tactical Communications)

Valdepeñas, Spain

Jan. 2018 - Dec. 2019

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Plan, organize and monitor tasks of the software development team.
- Design, develop and testing of Tactical Data Link solution software.
- · Integration of communications systems such as network controller, modem, radio, GPS, NTP server, radar and cryptographic device.
- · On-site system deployment, testing, support and training for Bangladesh navy on ships, ground stations and aircrafts.
- In-depth use of C++, STL, Boost, TCP/IP communications and multi-threading.

Tecnobit S.L.U. (Tactical Communications)

Valdepeñas, Spain

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Jun. 2014 - Dec. 2017

- Design, develop and testing of Tactical Data Link Systems including Link11, Link16, Link22, JREAP and SIMPLE protocols.
- Port a VxWorks Tactical Data Link processor application to Linux.
- Technologies used include C++11 and Qt.

VISILAB Research Group (UCLM)

Ciudad Real, Spain

RESEARCH ASSISTANT Sep. 2012 - May. 2014

- · Design and develop computer vision applications for desktop, Android and iOS platforms using OpenCV.
- [Book] OpenCV Essentials, Packt Publishing, 2014.
- [Article] A Vision-Based Localization Algorithm for an Indoor Navigation App, Eighth International Conference on Next Generation Mobile Apps, Services and Technologies (NGMAST), 2014.

Education

Expert in Video Games Development

Ciudad Real, Spain

UCLM (University of Castilla - La Mancha)

Sep. 2013 - Jun. 2014

B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering
UCLM (UNIVERSITY OF CASTILLA - LA MANCHA)

Ciudad Real, Spain Sep. 2011 - Jun. 2013

OCEM (ONIVERSITY OF ONSTILE). EXTINATED

Erasmus Scholarship

Eindhoven, The Netherlands

TUE(EINDHOVEN UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY)

Sep. 2009 - Jul. 2010

Technical Engineering in Computer Systems

Ciudad Real, Spain

UCLM(University of Castilla - La Mancha)

Sep. 2007 - Jun. 2011

DECEMBER 14, 2022 JULIO PATON · RÉSUMÉ